A Guide to the Faculty Senate Records, 1966-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Faculty Senate Records, 1966-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 30/3
9.8 cu. ft.; 7 boxes
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Faculty Senate.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The Faculty Senate was formed in 1969 by approval of the Board of Visitors to "articulate faculty views on campus policies and procedures." For more information on the Faculty Senate, including meeting minutes from 2003-present, see: http://www.facultysenate.vt.edu/.
Scope and Content
The minutes of the Faculty Senate, 1969 to 1990, make up the core of this collection. The minutes and reports of the Faculty Senate Steering Committee, 1967-69, also are included in this collection. Other materials, 1966-80, include: annual reports of the Senate presidents, cabinet minutes, constitutions and bylaws, correspondence, memoranda, minutes and reports of various committees and subcommittees, reports, and Senate rosters. Also included are scattered minutes and other materials dealing with the Commission on Faculty Affairs, Commission on Research and Graduate Studies, Commission on Student Affairs, Commission on Undergraduate Studies, Student Government Association, and University Council.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by year, then alphabetically by subject files.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Faculty Senate.
Subjects:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Local Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives
Contents List
- AAUP: Statement on Government of Colleges and Universities, 1966. (Box-folder 1-1)
- Home Economics Faculty Survey, 1966. (Box-folder 1-2)
- University Academic Council Minutes, 1966. (Box-folder 1-3)
- Steering Committee: Miscellaneous, 1966. (Box-folder 1-4)
- Steering Committee: Organizational Notice, 1966. (Box-folder 1-5)
- Constitution: General 1/2, 1967. (Box-folder 1-6)
- Constitution: General 2/2, 1967. (Box-folder 1-7)
- Constitution: Organization of Senate, 1967. (Box-folder 1-8)
- Constitution: Purpose and Function, 1967. (Box-folder 1-9)
- Steering Committee: Correspondence, 1967. (Box-folder 1-10)
- Steering Committee: Minutes, 1967. (Box-folder 1-11)
- Steering Committee: Miscellaneous, 1967. (Box-folder 1-12)
- Steering Committee: Positions, 1967. (Box-folder 1-13)
- Steering Committee: Relationship of Faculty Senate to Other University Governing Bodies, 1967. (Box-folder 1-14)
- Steering Committee: Rosters, 1967. (Box-folder 1-15)
- Comments on Proposed Faculty Senate Constitution and By-Laws, 1968. (Box-folder 1-16)
- Constitution and By-Laws, 1968. (Box-folder 1-17)
- Faculty Senate/University Council: Unified Constitution, 1968. (Box-folder 1-18)
- University Council Report: Subcommittee to Study Policies Related to Fraternities and Sororities, 1968. (Box-folder 1-19)
- Steering Committee: Correspondence, 1968. (Box-folder 1-20)
- Steering Committee: Leadership Conference at Virginia Commonwealth University, 1968. (Box-folder 1-21)
- Steering Committee: Minutes, 1968. (Box-folder 1-22)
- Steering Committee: Miscellaneous, 1968. (Box-folder 1-23)
- Steering Committee: Organizational Charts, 1968. (Box-folder 1-24)
- Steering Committee: Progress Reports, 1968. (Box-folder 1-25)
- Steering Committee: Schedules, 1968. (Box-folder 1-26)
- University Council: Constitution, 1968-1969. (Box-folder 1-27)
- Agendas, September 1969-May 1971. (Box-folder 1-28)
- Context Article on VPI Government: 1st, 2nd, and Final Drafts, 1969-1970. (Box-folder 1-29)
- Correspondence Received, 1969. (Box-folder 1-30)
- Correspondence Sent, 1969. (Box-folder 1-31)
- Elections and Organizations, 1969. (Box-folder 1-32)
- Faculty Leadership Conference, 1969. (Box-folder 1-33)
- Faculty AAUP Questionnaire, 1969. (Box-folder 1-34)
- Financial Records, 1969. (Box-folder 1-35)
- Goals of the Faculty Senate, 1969-1970. (Box-folder 1-36)
- Proposed Constitution and By-Laws, 1969. (Box-folder 1-37)
- Proposed Statement on Sabbatical Leave, 1969. (Box-folder 1-38)
- Minutes: Faculty Senate, 1969. (Box-folder 1-39)
- Minutes: Cabinet, 1969. (Box-folder 1-40)
- Minutes: Committees, 1969. (Box-folder 1-41)
- News Reports, 1969. (Box-folder 1-42)
- Progress Reports, 1969. (Box-folder 1-43)
- Resolution: FS-1, 1969. (Box-folder 1-44)
- Resolution: FS-2, 1969. (Box-folder 1-45)
- Resolution: FS-3, 1969. (Box-folder 1-46)
- Resolution: FS-4, 1969. (Box-folder 1-47)
- Resolution: FS-5, 1969. (Box-folder 1-48)
- Resolution: FS-6, 1969. (Box-folder 1-49)
- Resolution: FS-7, 1969. (Box-folder 1-50)
- Resolution: FS-8, 1969. (Box-folder 1-51)
- Resolution: FS-9, 1969. (Box-folder 1-52)
- Resolution: FS-10, 1969. (Box-folder 1-53)
- Senate Mailing and Telephone List, 1969-1973. (Box-folder 1-54)
- Strike, Disruption, and Related Events, 1969-1970. (Box-folder 1-55)
- University Name Poll and Miscellaneous, 1969. (Box-folder 1-56)
- Vote on Constitution and By-Laws, 1969. (Box-folder 1-57)
- American Association of University Professors Questionnaire, 1970. (Box-folder 2-58)
- Annual Report: Credentials and Elections Committee, May 1970. (Box-folder 2-59)
- Annual Report: Faculty Senate of VPI & SU, 1970-1971. (Box-folder 2-60)
- Boyle's Report on Proposed Sabbatical Policy, 1970. (Box-folder 2-61)
- Constitution of Statewide Senate, 1970. (Box-folder 2-62)
- Correspondence Received, 1970. (Box-folder 2-63)
- Correspondence Sent, 1970. (Box-folder 2-64)
- Credentials and Elections Committee, 1970. (Box-folder 2-65)
- Elections and Nominations, 1970. (Box-folder 2-66)
- General Notices of Faculty, 1970-1971. (Box-folder 2-67)
- Hammond's Speech: Reflections Upon Recent Campus Events, 1970. (Box-folder 2-68)
- Minutes: Faculty Senate, 1970. (Box-folder 2-69)
- Miscellaneous, 1970. (Box-folder 2-70)
- Objectives, 1970. (Box-folder 2-71)
- President's Annual Reports, 1970. (Box-folder 2-72)
- Progress Reports, 1970. (Box-folder 2-73)
- Proposed Amendments to Constitution and By-Laws, 1970. (Box-folder 2-74)
- Recommendations for an Addition to the Faculty Handbook, 1970. (Box-folder 2-75)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committees, Various, 1970. (Box-folder 2-76)
- Report: Committee on Campus Unrest, 1970. (Box-folder 2-77)
- Report: Committee on College Level Policies on Promotion, Salary, and Tenure Decisions, 1970. (Box-folder 2-78)
- Report: Committee on Plans: "Shared Responsibility," 1970. (Box-folder 2-79)
- Report: Faculty Senate Survey Schedule, 1970. (Box-folder 2-80)
- Report: Senate Survey Committee, May 1970.. (Box-folder 2-81)
- Report: University Library Committee, 1970-1971. (Box-folder 2-82)
- Reports of Various Commissions, Committees, etc., 1970. (Box-folder 2-83)
- Resolution: FS-11, 1970. (Box-folder 2-84)
- Resolution: FS-12, 1970. (Box-folder 2-85)
- Resolution: FS-13, 1970. (Box-folder 2-86)
- Resolution: FS-14, 1970. (Box-folder 2-87)
- Resolution: FS-15, 1970. (Box-folder 2-88)
- Resolution: FS-16, 1970. (Box-folder 2-89)
- Resolution: FS-17, 1970. (Box-folder 2-90)
- Resolution: FS-18, 1970. (Box-folder 2-91)
- Resolution: FS-19, 1970. (Box-folder 2-92)
- Resolution: FS-20, 1970. (Box-folder 2-93)
- Resolution: FS-21, 1970. (Box-folder 2-94)
- Resolution: FS-22, 1970. (Box-folder 2-95)
- Resolution: FS-23, 1970. (Box-folder 2-96)
- Resolution: FS-24, 1970. (Box-folder 2-97)
- Resolution: FS-25, 1970. (Box-folder 2-98)
- Resolution: FS-26, 1970. (Box-folder 2-99)
- Resolution: FS-27, 1970. (Box-folder 2-100)
- Rosters 1970. (Box-folder 2-101)
- Agendas, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-102)
- Correspondence, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-103)
- Expenses, 1971-1973. (Box-folder 2-104)
- A Justification of Tenure: "The Report of the President," Yale University, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-105)
- Meeting Arrangements, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-106)
- Memorandums: Administration, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-107)
- Minutes: Faculty Senate, 1971. (Box-folder 2-108)
- Minutes: Commission on Faculty Affairs, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-109)
- Minutes: Commission on Research & Graduate Studies, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-110)
- Minutes: Commission on Student Affairs, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-111)
- Minutes: Commission on Undergraduate Studies, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-112)
- Minutes: University Council, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-113)
- Senate Organization, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-114)
- Report: AAUP, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-115)
- Report: Committee on Constitutional Revision, 1971. (Box-folder 2-116)
- Report: Committee on Patents, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 2-117)
- Report: Committee on Reconciliation, November 3, 1971. (Box-folder 2-118)
- Report: Credentials and Elections Committee, August 31, 1971. (Box-folder 2-119)
- Report: In Loco Parentis Committee, 1971. (Box-folder 2-120)
- Report: Faculty Senate of Virginia, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 3-121)
- Report: Traffic Committee, September 23, 1971. (Box-folder 3-122)
- Resolution: FS-28, January 20, 1971. (Box-folder 3-123)
- Resolution: FS-29, Janaury 26, 1971. (Box-folder 3-124)
- Resolution: FS-30, January 19, 1971. (Box-folder 3-125)
- Resolution: FS-31, January 19, 1971. (Box-folder 3-126)
- Resolution: FS-32A, 1971. (Box-folder 3-127)
- Resolution: FS-32B, 1971. (Box-folder 3-128)
- Resolution: FS-33, February 16, 1971. (Box-folder 3-129)
- Resolution: FS-34, March 15, 1971. (Box-folder 3-130)
- Resolution: FS-35, May 4, 1971. (Box-folder 3-131)
- Resolution: FS-36, May 18, 1971. (Box-folder 3-132)
- Resolution: FS-37, 1971. (Box-folder 3-133)
- Resolution: FS-38, October 5, 1971. (Box-folder 3-134)
- Resolution: FS-39, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 3-135)
- Resolution: FS-40, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 3-136)
- Resolutions Progress Report, September 1971 - September 1972. (Box-folder 3-137)
- Roster, 1971-1972. (Box-folder 3-138)
- Standing Committees: Annual Reports, 1971. (Box-folder 3-139)
- Traffic Committee Report, September 1971 - September 1972. (Box-folder 3-140)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty Status Decisions, 1972. (Box-folder 3-141)
- Agendas, August 1972 - May 1973. (Box-folder 3-142)
- Annual Report: Credentials and Elections Committees; Committee on Committees, October 3, 1972. (Box-folder 3-143)
- Annual Social, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 3-144)
- Centennial, 1972. (Box-folder 3-145)
- Commission on Faculty Affairs 1972-1973. (Box-folder 3-146)
- Consulting and Parallel Use of University Facilities November 2, 1972. (Box-folder 3-147)
- Correspondence, November - December 1972. (Box-folder 3-148)
- Credentials and Elections Committee, October 11, 1972. (Box-folder 3-149)
- Faculty Senate of Virginia: Review of FSV Meeting, November 4, 1972. (Box-folder 3-150)
- Faculty Senate of Virginia Questionnaire, 1972. (Box-folder 3-151)
- Graduate Assembly, January 25, 1972. (Box-folder 3-152)
- Minutes: Faculty Senate and Cabinet, 1972. (Box-folder 3-153)
- Minutes: Cabinet, 1972. (Box-folder 3-154)
- Policies in the Library, February 24, 1972. (Box-folder 3-155)
- Prepared by the College of Agricultural and Life Sciences Faculty Association's Ad Hoc Credit Union Committee For Use By University Employee Benefits Committee, November 27, 1972. (Box-folder 3-156)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on Final Examination Policy, May 24, 1972. (Box-folder 3-157)
- Report: Committee on Committees, 1972. (Box-folder 3-158)
- Report: Committee on Long Range Goals of the University, 1972. (Box-folder 3-159)
- Report: Committee on Registration Procedures, 1972. (Box-folder 3-160)
- Report: Committee on Student Records, 1972. (Box-folder 3-161)
- Report: In Loco Parentis Committee, 1972. (Box-folder 3-162)
- Report: Miscellaneous Reports to the Faculty Senate, 1972. (Box-folder 3-163)
- Report: Recognition of Excellence in Teaching, 1972. (Box-folder 3-164)
- Report: Recommendations to the Committee Studying Possible Revisions of the University Council Committee, 1972. (Box-folder 3-165)
- Report: Retirement Age for Faculty, 1972. (Box-folder 3-166)
- Report: Task Force for Innovative Approaches to Instruction, 1972. (Box-folder 3-167)
- Resolution: FS-42, 1972. (Box-folder 3-168)
- Resolution: FS-43, 1972. (Box-folder 3-169)
- Resolution: FS-44, 1972. (Box-folder 3-170)
- Resolution: FS-45, 1972. (Box-folder 3-171)
- Resolution: FS-46, 1972. (Box-folder 3-172)
- Resolution: FS-47, 1972. (Box-folder 3-173)
- Resolution: FS-48, 1972. (Box-folder 3-174)
- Resolution: FS-49, 1972. (Box-folder 3-175)
- Resolution: FS-50, 1972. (Box-folder 3-176)
- Resolution: FS-51, 1972. (Box-folder 3-177)
- Resolution: FS-52 (Resolution on Long Range Goals), 1972. (Box-folder 3-178)
- Resolution: FS-72-1, 1972. (Box-folder 3-179)
- Resolution: FS-72-2, 1972. (Box-folder 3-180)
- Resolution: FS-72-3, 1972. (Box-folder 3-181)
- Resolution: FS-72-4, November 21, 1972. (Box-folder 3-182)
- Resolution: FS-72-5, 1972. (Box-folder 3-183)
- Resolution: FS-72-6, 1972. (Box-folder 3-184)
- Retirement Age for Faculty, April 20, 1972. (Box-folder 3-185)
- Roster, 1972-1973. (Box-folder 3-186)
- Faculty Age-Service Distribution (As of August 7, 1972). (Box-folder 3-187)
- Tenure, 1972. (Box-folder 3-188)
- Commission on Academic Tenure in Higher Education, April 16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-189)
- Constitutions and By-Laws, 1973. (Box-folder 3-190)
- Correspondence, 1973-1974. (Box-folder 3-191)
- Dr. Hahn's Remarks to the Faculty Senate, 1973. (Box-folder 3-192)
- Elections and Nominations, 1973. (Box-folder 3-193)
- Financial, 1973-1974. (Box-folder 3-194)
- Interim Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Employee Benefits in Land Grant Universities and Colleges, 1973. (Box-folder 3-195)
- Letter to Earl J. Shiflet, Secretary of Education, Commonwealth of Virginia, January 16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-196)
- Letter to James Wiggert from Leslie F. Malpass, January 22, 1973. (Box-folder 3-197)
- Miscellaneous, 1973-1974. (Box-folder 3-198)
- Minutes, 1973. (Box-folder 3-199)
- Presentation at Annual Meeting of the Association of American Colleges, January 15, 1973. (Box-folder 3-200)
- President's Report, 1973. (Box-folder 3-201)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on Consulting Policies, 1973. (Box-folder 3-202)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on Revision of the Constitution of the University Council, 1973. (Box-folder 3-203)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on Tenure, March 1, 1973. (Box-folder 3-204)
- Report: Committee to Study the Honor System, 1973. (Box-folder 3-205)
- Resolutions: Progress Reports, October 16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-206)
- Resolution: FS-72-7, January 16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-207)
- Resolution: FS-72-8, January 16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-208)
- Resolution: FS-72-9, January 16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-209)
- Resolution: FS-72-10, February 27, 1973. (Box-folder 3-210)
- Resolution: FS-72-11, February 27, 1973. (Box-folder 3-211)
- Resolution: FS-72-12, February 23, 1973. (Box-folder 3-212)
- Resolution: FS-72-13, March 28, 1973. (Box-folder 3-213)
- Resolution: FS-72-14, March 28, 1973. (Box-folder 3-214)
- Resolution: FS-72-15, 1973. (Box-folder 3-215)
- Resolution: FS-72-16, 1973. (Box-folder 3-216)
- Resolution: FS-73-0, 1973. (Box-folder 3-217)
- Resolution: FS-73-1, 1973. (Box-folder 3-218)
- Resolution: FS-73-2, 1973. (Box-folder 3-219)
- Resolution: FS-73-3, 1973. (Box-folder 3-220)
- Resolution: FS-73-4, 1973. (Box-folder 3-221)
- Resolution: FS-73-5, 1973. (Box-folder 3-222)
- Roster, 1973-1974. (Box-folder 3-223)
- University Copyright Policy, 1973. (Box-folder 3-224)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty Status, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-225)
- Ad Hoc Survey Committee, 1974. (Box-folder 3-226)
- Committee on Reconciliation, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-227)
- Committee Reports, 1974. (Box-folder 3-228)
- Correspondence, December 1974 - May 1975. (Box-folder 3-229)
- Credentials and Elections, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-330)
- Finance, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-231)
- Hahn, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-232)
- Consulting Activities, Outside Employment, and Use of University Facilities, 1974. (Box-folder 3-233)
- Krebs, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-234)
- Minutes: Senate and Cabinet, 1974. (Box-folder 3-235)
- Miscellaneous, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-236)
- Policy and Programs, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-237)
- President, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-238)
- Resolutions, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-239)
- Resolutions: Report, 1974. (Box-folder 3-240)
- Resolution: FS-74-1, 1974. (Box-folder 3-241)
- Resolution: FS-74-2, 1974. (Box-folder 3-242)
- Roster, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-243)
- VITA Form, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-244)
- VPI Facilities: Educational Foundation, 1974-1975. (Box-folder 3-245)
- Agendas, 1975-1976. (Box-folder 4-246)
- By-Laws of Virginia Tech Athletic Association, 1975. (Box-folder 4-247)
- Correspondence, 1975-1976. (Box-folder 4-248)
- Finance, July 1975 - June 1976. (Box-folder 4-249)
- General, 1975. (Box-folder 4-250)
- Humanization Retreat, 1975. (Box-folder 4-251)
- Memorandum: Notices of Meetings, 1975. (Box-folder 4-252)
- Minutes, 1975. (Box-folder 4-253)
- Minutes: Cabinet, 1975-1976. (Box-folder 4-254)
- Nominees, 1975. (Box-folder 4-255)
- Notice of Meetings: Cabinet, August 1975 - April 1976. (Box-folder 4-256)
- Officers Meetings, October 1975 - July 1976. (Box-folder 4-257)
- Past President's Report, October 1975. (Box-folder 4-256)
- Policy Document, October 1975. (Box-folder 4-259)
- Resolution Progress Report, 1975-1976. (Box-folder 4-260)
- Resolution: FS-75-4, 1975. (Box-folder 4-261)
- Resolution: FS-75-5 (In Memory of Fred and Joan Dreiling), 1975. (Box-folder 4-262)
- Requisitions, September 1975 - October 1976. (Box-folder 4-263)
- Room Reservations, October 1975 - May 1976. (Box-folder 4-264)
- Roster, 1975-1976. (Box-folder 4-265)
- SCHEV Study, 1975. (Box-folder 4-266)
- Senate and Self-Study, 1975. (Box-folder 4-267)
- Stephen F. Austin Questionnaire, 1975. (Box-folder 4-268)
- Faculty Survey, March 1975. (Box-folder 4-269)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Consulting, 1976. (Box-folder 4-270)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Dislocation, 1976. (Box-folder 4-271)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Teaching Evaluation, 1976. (Box-folder 4-272)
- Agendas, 1976-1978. (Box-folder 4-273)
- Attendance, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-274)
- CFA: Academic Leave, 1976. (Box-folder 4-275)
- CIA, 1976. (Box-folder 4-276)
- Committee on Committees Election, 1976. (Box-folder 4-277)
- Condensed Reports: Council and Commissions, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-278)
- Consulting, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-279)
- Correspondence, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-280)
- Dues, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-281)
- Election Information: Vitae, etc., 1976. (Box-folder 4-282)
- Employee Benefit Analysis, 1976. (Box-folder 4-283)
- Evaluating of Teaching (SPOT Report), 1976. (Box-folder 4-284)
- Faculty Senate of Virginia, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-285)
- Finances, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-286)
- Interest Survey, 1976. (Box-folder 4-287)
- Memorandums, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-288)
- Minutes, 1976. (Box-folder 4-289)
- Minutes: Cabinet, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-290)
- Notice of Cabinet Meetings, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-291)
- Progress Report from the Ad Hoc Committee of the Faculty Senate to Study Architectural Barriers to the Physically and Sensorially Handicapped at Virginia Tech, 1976. (Box-folder 4-292)
- Report: Faculty Senate Committee to Study Gun Regulations, 1976. (Box-folder 4-293)
- Representation on Faculty Senate, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-294)
- Requisitions, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-295)
- Resolution: FS-76-1 (Library Facilities), 1976. (Box-folder 4-296)
- Resolution: FS-76-2 (Gun Control), 1976. (Box-folder 4-297)
- Responses to Committee Info, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-298)
- Room Reservations, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-299)
- Roster, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-300)
- SPOT Report of University Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty Evaluation, November 1976. (Box-folder 4-301)
- Task Force on University Development, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-302)
- University Committee Reports, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 4-303)
- Condensed Reports: University Council and Commissions, 1977. (Box-folder 4-304)
- Correspondence, 1977. (Box-folder 4-305)
- Election of Representatives, Spring 1977. (Box-folder 4-306)
- Financial: Receipts, 1977. (Box-folder 4-307)
- Graduate Student Progress Review, 1977. (Box-folder 4-308)
- Membership on University Committees, 1977. (Box-folder 4-309)
- Minutes, 1977. (Box-folder 4-310)
- Minutes: Cabinet, 1977. (Box-folder 4-311)
- Miscellaneous, 1977. (Box-folder 4-312)
- Promotion and Tenure Data, 1977. (Box-folder 4-313)
- Report: Ad Hoc Senate Committee on Dislocation, 1977. (Box-folder 4-314)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on University Governance, 1977. (Box-folder 4-315)
- Resolution: FS-77-1, 1977. (Box-folder 4-316)
- Resolution: FS-77-2, 1977. (Box-folder 4-317)
- Room Reservations, 1977. (Box-folder 4-318)
- Agendas, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-319)
- Committee on Graduate Studies, 1978. (Box-folder 4-320)
- Correspondence, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-321)
- Elections and Nominations, 1978. (Box-folder 4-322)
- Faculty Senate of Virginia President's Report, 1978. (Box-folder 4-323)
- Memoranda, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-324)
- Minutes 1/2, 1978. (Box-folder 4-325)
- Minutes 2/2, 1978. (Box-folder 4-326)
- Minutes: Cabinet, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-327)
- Miscellaneous, 1978. (Box-folder 4-328)
- President's Address, 1978. (Box-folder 4-329)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on Committees [Draft], 1978. (Box-folder 4-330)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty Senate Policy Document, 1978. (Box-folder 4-331)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on University Governance: Proposed Resolution, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-332)
- Report: Committee on Procedures for Evaluating Department Heads, 1978. (Box-folder 4-333)
- Report: Faculty Senate Benefits Committee, 1978. (Box-folder 4-334)
- Report: Internal Communications Committee, 1978. (Box-folder 4-335)
- Report: Student-Faculty Committee to Study VPI Facilities, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-336)
- Resolution: FS-78-2, 1978. (Box-folder 4-337)
- Resolution: FS-78-3, 1978. (Box-folder 4-338)
- Resolution: FS-78-4, 1978. (Box-folder 4-339)
- Resolution: FS-78-5, 1978. (Box-folder 4-340)
- Resolution: Proposal to Form Committee on Academic and Scholarly Matters, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-341)
- Roster, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-342)
- Student Legal Services, 1978. (Box-folder 4-343)
- University Decisions on Promotions and Tenure, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 4-344)
- Correspondence, 1979. (Box-folder 5-345)
- Minutes, 1979. (Box-folder 5-346)
- Miscellaneous, 1979. (Box-folder 5-347)
- Proposal for the Resident Doctor of Education Degree Programs at the Dulles Facility, 1979. (Box-folder 5-348)
- Recommended Changes in Faculty Handbook, 1979. (Box-folder 5-349)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee to Compile Faculty Senate Policy Document, 1979. (Box-folder 5-350)
- Report: Committee on Committees: Nominations, 1979. (Box-folder 5-351)
- Resolution: FS-79-1, 1979. (Box-folder 5-352)
- Resolution: FS-79-2, 1979. (Box-folder 5-353)
- University Governance, 1979. (Box-folder 5-354)
- Minutes, 1980. (Box-folder 5-355)
- Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box-folder 5-356)
- Officers 1969-1970 to 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5-357)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee to Compile Faculty Senate Policy Document, 1980. (Box-folder 5-358)
- Minutes, 1981. (Box-folder 5-359)
- Report: Ad Hoc Committee on the Collins Report, 1981-1982. (Box-folder 5-360)
- Roster, 1981. (Box-folder 5-361)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Affirmative Action, 1982-1983. (Box-folder 5-362)
- Collins Report, 1982. (Box-folder 5-363)
- Constitution and By-Laws, 1982. (Box-folder 5-364)
- Correspondence, 1982. (Box-folder 5-365)
- Early Quarter System, 1982. (Box-folder 5-366)
- Elections and Nominations, 1982. (Box-folder 5-367)
- Financial, 1982-1984. (Box-folder 5-368)
- Guidelines for Inter-collegiate and Inter-departmental Cooperation in the Design and Teaching of Courses, 1982. (Box-folder 5-369)